ADRIANA GUERRA

adriana.luz.guerra@gmail.com 📞 +1 949 763 8167 (🛍 linkedin.com/in/a-l-guerra





SKILLS

- JavaScript
- C#
- .NET Framework
- HTML
- CSS
- SQL
- Python
- .NET CORE
- ASP.NET
- VB.NET
- VBA

EDUCATION UC BERKELEY

BA in Cognitive Science

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership
- Teaching/Mentoring
- Troubleshooting
- Communication

LANGUAGES

- English: Native
- Spanish: Fluent
- French: Proficient

ADDITIONAL

US Citizen References and additional experience available upon request.

PROFILE

I am a self-motivated developer dedicated to the pursuit of well-designed software and systems. Working in a variety of fields, from SCUBA diving to neuroscience research, has given me the opportunity to develop strong skills in the interpretation of user needs and to apply my development skills to wide a variety of projects. I am interested in working in an Agile environment to develop efficient applications that are user-friendly and scalable.

EXPERIENCE

PROGRAMMER III • Texas Health and Human Services, Jul 2019 - Present

- Worked with customer to redefine the scope and prioritize the functions of a .NET web application that had been on hold since 2018 so that I could bring the application to life.
- Developed a file uploading and data processing web-app using .NET Razor pages, C#, MSSQL, JavaScript, JQuery, and HTML.
- Translated complex data processing logic into SQL stored procedures to update records.
- Developed SQL stored procedures to clean addresses and to match records by address (using Levenshtein Ratios).
- Used Razor Pages, C#, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, and CSS to updated a .NET website to meet specifications provided by a user experience designer.
- Used AWS to deploy updates to a .NET website.
- Developed documentation for updating and deploying a .NET website on AWS.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER • Bubble Manager & Bubble Cert, Aug 2017 - Present

- With a partner, developed customized SaaS business management software for SCUBA centers using MS Access and VBA that is currently used at 19 centers in 4 countries.
- · Streamlined the customer registration process through a dynamic and responsive web-form using ASP.NET, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery.
- Simplified customer enrollment with international SCUBA agencies by posting customer data directly to dive agency web-servers from the business management system using VBA and WinHTTP requests.
- Developed Batch and PowerShell scripts to automate the data management software installation and configuration.
- Built a web-app for SCUBA instructors and SCUBA centers using ASP.NET, .NET Framework, VB.NET, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, and REST API to simplify the registration and certification of students with international SCUBA agencies.

PROGRAM COORDINATOR • Roctopus Pro Center, Thailand, Jun - Sep 2018

- Reorganized and oversaw a SCUBA professional training program.
- Developed a training schedule to maximize opportunities for trainees while minimizing redundant work for limited staff.
- Created Google Sheet and Google Script based program management tools to track student training progress easily.
- Updated design and content of the website using WordPress and Google Analytics.
- Developed email templates using HTML and CSS.
- Oversaw social media and responded to program inquiries.

SCUBA INSTRUCTOR • Sairee Cottage Diving, Thailand, Nov 2013 - Jan 2018

- Worked as a head SCUBA instructor at a SCUBA resort in one of the busiest diving destinations in the world.
- Taught students of all levels, from introductory experiences to courses for aspiring professionals.
- Received 5 student-elected PADI recognition awards for my teaching.
- Organized SCUBA trips and mentored interns while teaching courses.

STAFF RESEARCH ASSOCIATE • UC San Diego, Sep 2010 - Aug 2012

- Worked with the Research on Aging and Development Lab and the Swartz Center for Computational Neuroscience.
- Collected neurobehavioral measures (i.e. electroencephalography, eye tracking, body-motion capture, and behavioral tests) from typical and clinical populations.
- Analyzed data using specialized software.
- Developed protocols and Python scripts to test the accuracy of datastream integration from data sources with varying sampling rates.